Andrew Hamerly

Cleveland/Akron, OH | Phone: (440) 429-4059 ah@andrewhamerly.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewhamerly3

SUMMARY

Website maintenance specialist with a robust background in web development languages and frameworks, digital marketing, and client project management. Strong attention to detail with both written and verbal communication skills while collaborating with teams. Proactive in ensuring the functionality, security, and performance of client websites with analytics and uptime monitors.

SKILLS

Tech Skills: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript ES6 | Node.js | Express.js | PostgreSQL | WordPress CMS | WooCommerce | SEO | Ahrefs | Digital Marketing | Email Marketing | Balsamiq Wireframes | Notion

Soft Skills: Fast-Learner | Client Project Management | Problem-Solving | Attention to Detail | Initiative | Effective Communication | Systems Thinking | Positive Attitude | Team-Player

RECENT FRONTEND PROJECT

Chasing the Golden Hours (Web App) | https://andrewhamerly.github.io/ChasingtheGoldenHours/ Description: As a sunset photographer, I want to see the sunset time for multiple cities with directions and weather, so I can plan my photoshoot times accordingly.

Role: Created the project idea, wireframe, CSS, weather functions, and project management.

Tech: Balsamiq Wireframes | Bulma CSS Framework | jQuery UI | jQuery | DayJS | Google API |
Sunrise Sunset API | Notion Project Management | Git | GitHub | GitHub Pages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Website Development, SEO, and Email Marketing, October 2018 - Present *Self-Employed, Cleveland, OH*

Created over 15 client websites for small business, retail, and E-commerce brands. Currently, maintain and update 10 client WordPress websites with security and performance best practices.

Website Developer, February 2023 - Present

Ascension Biomedical, Oberlin, OH

Developed and currently maintain an Ohio Medical Marijuana Control Program compliant website that passed meticulous review by the State of Ohio Division of Cannabis Control.

Digital Marketing Manager, October 2019 - January 2023

Organic Plus Brands, Home of Whole Plant $^{\text{TM}}$ and Plant Puff $^{\text{TM}}$, Cleveland, OH

Developed and implemented a modern digital marketing strategy to drive eCommerce **sales 4x**. Built the strategy, content, and websites for three in-house brands resulting in **over 350k** in online sales.

EDUCATION

Case Western Reserve University, Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate An intensive program for gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, PostgreSQL, Sequalize, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, and Handelbars.js.

Baldwin Wallace University, Bachelor in Arts in Innovation & Entrepreneurship and Business Administration, Berea, OH 2017

Cuyahoga Community College, Associate of Applied Business in Purchasing and Supply Chain Management, Cleveland, OH 2015